<tools>
  <tool name="web_search">
    <description>Search the web using Perplexity AI for real-time information and current events.

This is your PRIMARY research tool - use it extensively and liberally for:
- Current vulnerabilities, CVEs, and security advisories
- Latest attack techniques, exploits, and proof-of-concepts
- Technology-specific security research and documentation
- Target reconnaissance and OSINT gathering
- Security tool documentation and usage guides
- Incident response and threat intelligence
- Compliance frameworks and security standards
- Bug bounty reports and security research findings
- Security conference talks and research papers

The tool provides intelligent, contextual responses with current information that may not be in your training data. Use it early and often during security assessments to gather the most up-to-date factual information.</description>
    <details>This tool leverages Perplexity AI's sonar-reasoning model to search the web and provide intelligent, contextual responses to queries. It's essential for effective cybersecurity work as it provides access to the latest vulnerabilities, attack vectors, security tools, and defensive techniques. The AI understands security context and can synthesize information from multiple sources.</details>
    <parameters>
      <parameter name="query" type="string" required="true">
        <description>The search query or question you want to research. Be specific and include relevant technical terms, version numbers, or context for better results. Make it as detailed as possible, with the context of the current security assessment.</description>
      </parameter>
    </parameters>
    <returns type="Dict[str, Any]">
      <description>Response containing: - success: Whether the search was successful - query: The original search query - content: AI-generated response with current information - message: Status message</description>
    </returns>
    <examples>
  # Found specific service version during reconnaissance
  <function=web_search>
  <parameter=query>I found OpenSSH 7.4 running on port 22. Are there any known exploits or privilege escalation techniques for this specific version?</parameter>
  </function>

  # Encountered WAF blocking attempts
  <function=web_search>
  <parameter=query>Cloudflare is blocking my SQLmap attempts on this login form. What are the latest bypass techniques for Cloudflare WAF in 2024?</parameter>
  </function>

  # Need to exploit discovered CMS
  <function=web_search>
  <parameter=query>Target is running WordPress 5.8.3 with WooCommerce 6.1.1. What are the current RCE exploits for this combination?</parameter>
  </function>

  # Stuck on privilege escalation
  <function=web_search>
  <parameter=query>I have low-privilege shell on Ubuntu 20.04 with kernel 5.4.0-74-generic. What local privilege escalation exploits work for this exact kernel version?</parameter>
  </function>

  # Need lateral movement in Active Directory
  <function=web_search>
  <parameter=query>I compromised a domain user account in Windows Server 2019 AD environment. What are the best techniques to escalate to Domain Admin without triggering EDR?</parameter>
  </function>

  # Encountered specific error during exploitation
  <function=web_search>
  <parameter=query>Getting "Access denied" when trying to upload webshell to IIS 10.0. What are alternative file upload bypass techniques for Windows IIS?</parameter>
  </function>

  # Need to bypass endpoint protection
  <function=web_search>
  <parameter=query>Target has CrowdStrike Falcon running. What are the latest techniques to bypass this EDR for payload execution and persistence?</parameter>
  </function>

  # Research target's infrastructure for attack surface
  <function=web_search>
  <parameter=query>I found target company "AcmeCorp" uses Office 365 and Azure. What are the common misconfigurations and attack vectors for this cloud setup?</parameter>
  </function>

  # Found interesting subdomain during recon
  <function=web_search>
  <parameter=query>Discovered staging.target.com running Jenkins 2.401.3. What are the current authentication bypass and RCE exploits for this Jenkins version?</parameter>
  </function>

  # Need alternative tools when primary fails
  <function=web_search>
  <parameter=query>Nmap is being detected and blocked by the target's IPS. What are stealthy alternatives for port scanning that evade modern intrusion prevention systems?</parameter>
  </function>

  # Finding best security tools for specific tasks
  <function=web_search>
  <parameter=query>What is the best Python pip package in 2025 for JWT security testing and manipulation, including cracking weak secrets and algorithm confusion attacks?</parameter>
  </function>
    </examples>
  </tool>
</tools>
