<tools>
  <tool name="think">
    <description>Use the tool to think about something. It will not obtain new information or change the
  database. Use it when complex reasoning or some cache memory is needed.</description>
    <details>This tool creates dedicated space for structured thinking during complex tasks,
  particularly useful for:
  - Tool output analysis: When you need to carefully process the output of previous tool calls
  - Policy-heavy environments: When you need to follow detailed guidelines and verify compliance
  - Sequential decision making: When each action builds on previous ones and mistakes are costly
  - Multi-step problem solving: When you need to break down complex problems into manageable steps</details>
    <parameters>
      <parameter name="thought" type="string" required="true">
        <description>The thought or reasoning to record</description>
      </parameter>
    </parameters>
    <returns type="Dict[str, Any]">
      <description>Response containing: - success: Whether the thought was recorded successfully - message: Confirmation message with character count or error details</description>
    </returns>
    <examples>
  # Planning and strategy
  <function=think>
  <parameter=thought>I need to analyze the scan results systematically. First, let me review
  the open ports: 22 (SSH), 80 (HTTP), 443 (HTTPS), and 3306 (MySQL). The MySQL port being
  externally accessible is a high priority security concern. I should check for default
  credentials and version information. For the web services, I need to enumerate
  directories and test for common web vulnerabilities.</parameter>
  </function>

  # Analysis of tool outputs
  <function=think>
  <parameter=thought>The Nmap scan revealed 15 open ports, but three stand out as concerning:
  - Port 3306 (MySQL) - Database should not be exposed externally
  - Port 5432 (PostgreSQL) - Another database port that's risky when public
  - Port 6379 (Redis) - Often misconfigured and can lead to data exposure
  I should prioritize testing these database services for authentication bypass and
  information disclosure vulnerabilities.</parameter>
  </function>

  # Decision making and next steps
  <function=think>
  <parameter=thought>Based on the vulnerability scan results, I've identified several critical
  issues that need immediate attention:
  1. SQL injection in the login form (confirmed with sqlmap)
  2. Reflected XSS in the search parameter
  3. Directory traversal in the file upload function
  I should document these findings with proof-of-concept exploits and assign appropriate
  CVSS scores. The SQL injection poses the highest risk due to potential data
  exfiltration.</parameter>
  </function>
    </examples>
  </tool>
</tools>
